Fahim Salam Chowdhury

Software Engineer

+8801913056486 | https://fahim44.github.io | fahim.cse11@gmail.com |

House: 27, Road: 11, Sector: 14, Uttara, Dhaka, Bangladesh

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Empirical software engineer with 4 years of experience developing mobile applications for both small and high volume businesses. Played a vital role in development of both business and technical arena and achieved a significant boost for few companies. An enthusiastic team player with quick learning ability.

EXPERIENCE

TEAM MEMBER – SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TEAM | ONNOROKOM WEB SERVICES LIMITED | DHAKA, BANGLADESH

September 2020 - Present

Onnorokom Web Services Limited is one of the fastest growing software service provider in the Bangladsh. Rokomari.com is a sister concern of Onnorokom Web Services Limited. Rokomari.com is one of the leading e-commerce organizations in Bangladesh. It is the biggest online bookstore in Bangladesh.

Responsibilities and success:

- Design and develop scale-able & high efficient back-end services.
- Provide support for android application development.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Java, Spring-boot, Micro-service architecture.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER – TEAM LEAD | DAILYGOODS LTD. | DHAKA, BANGLADESH September 2019 – August 2020

Dailygoods Ltd. is developing online courier service solution and e-commerce application.

Responsibilities and success:

- lead a team of 3 high performing engineers
- Develop various libraries to support various applications
- Distribute tasks among the team
- Design scale-able architecture of various projects
- Technologies: Android, Spring framework, Vaadin framework, Java

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FRENCLUB MOBILE LTD. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

January 2017 - August 2019

Frenclub Mobile Ltd. develops social media and productivity applications for Chinese, Malaysian, Indonesian market. They are well known for their VAS services.

Responsibilities and success:

- Created and maintained technical documentation and acted as liaison between QA and development team
- led a team of 3 high performing engineers
- Improved code stability and application security
- Implemented in-app purchase system
- Gained performance boost by 3x
- Developed applications used by thousands
- Technologies: Android, Java, SQLite, GCM, FCM, Firebase, iOS, Swift-2.3

APP DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER | SOFTWIND TECH LTD. | Dhaka, Bangladesh January 2016 - December 2016

Softwind Tech Ltd. is well known for their digital marketing services. They also provide various interactive web, game, mobile application solutions to their customers to boost their marketing.

Responsibilities and success:

- Created and maintained project schedule and acted as liaison between business, QA and development team
- Developed application in shortest amount of time
- Developed applications for android, ios, windows phone
- Worked with a team of 3 high performing engineers
- <u>Technologies</u>: Android, Xamarin, Windows phone, Java, SQLite, C#

EDUCATION

MSc in CS | Jahangirnagar university | Savar, Bangladesh

2018

• CGPA: 3.43 (out of 4)

BSc in CSE | Military Institute of Science and Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh 2011 – 2015

• CGPA: 2.99 (out of 4)

CERTIFICATIONS

Mobile Apps Development course | CSE Dept., MIST

2015

PROFILES

LinkedIn: https://tinyurl.com/uo7apac

StackOverflow: https://tinyurl.com/v8aud4m

Github: https://tinyurl.com/qo2x4uw